tastesbetterfromscratch.com 2019-03-31

# Privacy Policy - Tastes Better From Scratch

**Privacy Policy**

Effective as of May 25, 2018

 **Welcome to Tastes Better From Scratch**

Tastes Better From Scratch has created this Privacy Policy in order to set forth the principles governing our information-gathering and dissemination practices, including but not limited to such activities as forums, chat rooms, personal profile pages, product reviews, article commentary, blogs, RSS feeds and newsletters, among other offerings. Tastes Better From Scratch has a strong commitment to the privacy of our users. Please note that this Privacy Policy applies only to information collected through Tastes Better From Scratch and not to information collected offline or to information you may provide to any third-party sites to which Tastes Better From Scratch may link, except as expressly provided herein.

 **Information We Collect**

While using our Site, we may ask you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information that can be used to contact or identify you. Personally identifiable information may include, but is not limited to your name and email address.

When we collect Personally Identifiable Information from you, you will have the opportunity to “opt in” and “opt out” to receive email or other digital communications from us and/or our business partners.

If you have submitted your personal information to Tastes Better from Scratch, you may correct, amend or delete the Personally Identifiable Information maintained on file about you if it is incorrect.

In all cases, we will only use your information as permitted by law. Notwithstanding any other provision of this Privacy Policy, however, we may disclose Personally Identifiable Information to others if we are required to do so by law or we in good faith believe that such action is necessary to (a) comply with the law or with legal process; (b) protect and defend our rights and property; (c) protect against misuse or unauthorized use of the Site; or (d) protect the personal safety or property of our users or the public. Please note that we may not provide you with notice prior to disclosure in such cases.

 **Use of “Cookies”**

A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. Cookies may be either “persistent” cookies or “session” cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.  Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

We use cookies for the following purposes:

(a) authentication – we use cookies to identify you when you visit our website and as you navigate our website

(b) [personalization – we use cookies to store information about your preferences and to personalize the website for you;

(c) security – we use cookies as an element of the security measures used to protect user accounts, including preventing fraudulent use of login credentials, and to protect our website and services generally

(d) advertising – we use cookies to help us to display advertisements that will be relevant to you

(e) analysis – we use cookies to help us to analyze the use and performance of our website and services

We use Google Analytics to analyze the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. Google’s privacy policy is available at: <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>

Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies and to delete cookies. The methods for doing so vary from browser to browser, and from version to version. You can however obtain up-to-date information about blocking and deleting cookies via these links:

(a) <https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en> (Chrome);

(b) <https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences>(Firefox);

(c) <http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/> (Opera);

(d) <https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies> (Internet Explorer);

(e) <https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411> (Safari); and

(f) <https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy> (Edge).

Please note that blocking cookies may have a negative impact on the functions of many websites, including our Site. Some features of the Site may cease to be available to you.

 **Interest-Based Advertising**

Advertising Privacy Statement

This Site is affiliated with AdThrive, LLC (“AdThrive”) for the purposes of placing advertising on the Site.  AdThrive uses standard and widely-available tools for the placement and serving of ads, including those provided by Google, Inc. and its affiliates. We publish interest-based advertisements on the Site; that is, ads that are tailored to reflect your interests. To help understand your interests, AdThrive, Google and our other advertising partners will track your behaviour on our website and on other websites across the Internet using cookies.

By using this Site, you consent to the use of such cookies and the sharing of data captured by such cookies with AdThrive, Google, and our other third party partners.You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/). You can also opt out of the network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative’s multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: [http://optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/).  However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained.

For European Economic Area Residents

If you reside in a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), then under the GDPR and applicable data protection laws you have the rights, among other things, to access your personal data, have us erase it, and/or restrict its further processing.  If you wish to access or delete your personal data (if any) maintained by us or AdThrive related to advertising on the Site, you can contact AdThrive at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) If you wish to see a list of the advertising partners we work with or change which of those partners track your behavior using cookies, click the ad preferences icon. (Available in the EU.)

 **Email Addresses**

We may collect your email address, but only if you voluntarily provide it to us. This may occur, for example, if you sign up to receive an email newsletter, or enter a promotion. We will use your email address for the purposes for which you provided it to us, and also from time to time to send you emails regarding the Site or other products or services that we believe may be of interest to you.  You may opt out of such email communications at any time by clicking the “unsubscribe” button in the email.

Your email address may also be shared with the technology provider we use in connection with the purposes for which you provided it, and that technology provider may also contact you from time to time.

If you are a resident of a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), we do not wish to receive your email address, and will delete it you have provided it inadvertently.

 **Sale of Business or Assets**

In the event that the Site or substantially all of its assets is sold or disposed of as a going concern, whether by merger, sale of assets or otherwise, or in the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy or receivership, the information we have collected about you may be one of the assets sold or merged in connection with that transaction.

 **Links to Third Party Web Sites**

Tastes Better from Scratch includes links to external, or third party websites. Tastes Better from Scratch’s privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or websites.

 **Security**

The security of your Personal Information is important to us but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. We never sell your personal information to third parties.

 **COPPA**

When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under the age of 13 years old, the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, United States’ consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children’s privacy and safety online.

We do not specifically market to children under the age of 13 years old.

 **Financial Relationships**

Please note that Tastes Better From Scratch may have financial relationships with some of the merchants/vendors mentioned on this website. In some instances, Tastes Better From Scratch may be compensated if consumers choose to utilize the links located throughout the content on this site and generate sales for said merchant/vendor.

 **Limitation of Liability**

TASTES BETTER FROM SCRATCH PROVIDES THE INFORMATION, SERVICES AND PRODUCTS ON THIS WEB SITES “AS IS” WITHOUT WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND. YOU AGREE THAT TASTES BETTER FROM SCRATCH SHALL NOT BE RESPONSIBLE FOR ANY CONTENT FOUND ON OUR FORUMS THAT ANY DOWNLOADING OF MATERIALS FOUND ON OR THROUGH TASTES BETTER FROM SCRATCH FORUMS IS DONE AT YOUR OWN RISK, AND THAT TASTES BETTER FROM SCRATCH IS NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR UNSOLICITED COMMUNICATIONS THAT ARISE FROM YOUR POSTINGS. TASTES BETTER FROM SCRATCH SHALL NOT BE RESPONSIBLE IN ANY MANNER FOR THE ACTS OF ANY THIRD PARTY, INCLUDING WITOUT LIMITATION, ANY THIRD PARTY AD NETWORK.

 **Changes to the Privacy Policy**

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. The most recent version of the Privacy Policy will always be posted on the Site, with the “Effective Date” posted at the top of the Policy. We may revise and update this Privacy Policy if our practices change, as technology changes, or as we add new services or change existing ones. If we make any material changes to our Privacy Policy or how we handle your personal information, or we are going to use any personal information in a manner that is materially different from that stated in our Privacy Policy at the time we collected such information, we will give you a reasonable opportunity to consent to the change. If you do not consent, your personal information will be used as agreed to under the terms of the privacy policy in effect at the time we obtained that information. By using our Site or services after the Effective Date, you are deemed to consent to our then-current privacy policy. We will use information previously obtained in accordance with the Privacy Policy in effect when the information was obtained from you.

 **Contacting Us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, or the practices of this Site, please contact us [here](https://tastesbetterfromscratch.com/contact/).

 **Amazon Services LLC Associates Program  **

 ** _What’s an affiliate program?_**

Sometimes when I link to products we love, I get a small commission from sales or views of that product. Affiliate links are one of the ways I cover the costs of running this website and help support my family.

 **AMAZON DISCLOSURE:**

Tastes Better From Scratch LLC is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to Amazon.com

 **Nutritional Information Disclaimer**

The writers and publishers of tastesbetterfromscratch.com are not nutritionists or registered dietitians.

This website and recipes on tastesbetterfromscratch.com, are produced for informational purposes only. Statements within this site have not been evaluated or approved by the Food and Drug Administration. This website is not intended to cure, prevent, diagnose or treat any disease. Content should not be considered a substitute for professional medical advice, expertise or treatment.

The reader assumes full responsibility for consulting a qualified health professional regarding health conditions or concerns, and before starting a new health program or diet. The writer(s) and publisher(s) of this site are not responsible for adverse reactions, effects, or consequences resulting from the use of any suggestions ore recipes herein or procedures undertaken hereafter.

This website is not intended as nutritional advice and readers of this website are ultimately responsible for all decisions pertaining to their health.

Occasionally, this website, tastesbetterfromscratch.com, may offer estimated nutritional information for recipes contained on this website, such as calories, fat, carbs, etc. This information is provided as a courtesy and is not guaranteed to be accurate. This nutritional information comes from online calculators. Although tastesbetterfromscratch.com attempts to provide accurate nutritional information, these figures are only estimates.

Various factors can change the nutritional information in any given recipe. These factors include but are not limited to the actual brands used. Also, different online calculators sometimes provide different results based on their own algorithms and nutrition fact sources. Under no circumstances will tastesbetterfromscratch.com and the recipe creators be responsible for any loss or damage resulting from your reliance on the nutritional information that may be provided.

To obtain the most accurate representation of the nutritional information in any given recipe, you should calculate the nutritional information with the actual ingredients you use in your recipe, using your preferred nutrition calculator, or your own nutritionist or medical professional.  **You are solely responsible for ensuring that any nutritional information obtained is accurate.**

The writer(s) and publisher(s) of tastesbetterfromscratch.com are not responsible for adverse reactions, consequences or effects, resulting from the use of any recipes or suggestions herein or procedures undertaken hereafter. This website is not intended as nutritional advice and readers of this website are ultimately responsible for all decisions pertaining to their health.

This website is not intended as nutritional advice and readers of this website are ultimately responsible for all decisions pertaining to their health.

© TASTES BETTER FROM SCRATCH.  All images & content are copyright protected. Please do not use my images without prior permission. If you want to republish a recipe, please re-create the recipe, use your own photo, and re-write the recipe in your own words, or link back to the recipe on TastesBetterFromScratch.com.

 _Last updated: June 2018_
